<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-28T09:58:53+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The JCMS series</title><subtitle>The Joint Condensed Matter Seminar (JCMS) series is organised by KTH Royal Insitute of Technology, Nordita, and Stockholm University.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/marin-bukov.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov" /><published>2022-07-30T13:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T13:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/marin-bukov</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/marin-bukov.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;november-28th-2022-marin-bukov&quot;&gt;November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, November 28th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Marin Bukov&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Max Planck Institute for the Physics of Complex Systems, Dresden&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 31st, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/apoorv-tiwari.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 31st, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari" /><published>2022-07-30T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/apoorv-tiwari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/apoorv-tiwari.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;october-31st-2022-apoorv-tiwari&quot;&gt;October 31st, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, October 31st, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Apoorv Tiwari&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;KTH, Royal Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 31st, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 24th, 2022: Loic Herviou</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/loic-herviou.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 24th, 2022: Loic Herviou" /><published>2022-07-30T11:50:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T11:50:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/loic-herviou</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/loic-herviou.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;october-24th-2022-loic-herviou&quot;&gt;October 24th, 2022: Loic Herviou&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, October 24th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Loic Herviou&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;EPFL, Lausanne&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 24th, 2022: Loic Herviou</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 17th, 2022: Rodrigo Arouca</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/rodrigo-arouca.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 17th, 2022: Rodrigo Arouca" /><published>2022-07-30T11:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T11:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/rodrigo-arouca</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/rodrigo-arouca.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;october-17th-2022-rodrigo-arouca&quot;&gt;October 17th, 2022: Rodrigo Arouca&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, October 17th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Rodrigo Arouca&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Uppsala University&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exceptionally Enhanced Topological Superconductivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 17th, 2022: Rodrigo Arouca</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 3rd, 2022: Giulia Venditti</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/giulia-venditti.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 3rd, 2022: Giulia Venditti" /><published>2022-07-30T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/giulia-venditti</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/giulia-venditti.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;october-3rd-2022-giulia-venditti&quot;&gt;October 3rd, 2022: Giulia Venditti&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, October 3rd, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Giulia Venditti&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;SPIN-CNR, Rome&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filamentary Superconductivity in Systems with Competing Charge Density Wave&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filamentary superconductivity is naturally emerging as a new rich field. The higly inhomogeneous nature of the superconducting (SC) condensate has been in fact reported in several families of low dimensional superconductors. The mechanisms behind the fragmentation of the electronic condensate can be several, depending on the specific material and conditions, leading to unusual trends in transport measurements [1] and covering the hallmarks of a Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless (BKT) transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some class of materials, experimental observations points towards the direction of a phase competition among superconductivity and the charge ordered phase, tunable through an external control parameter, which can be either magnetic field, pressure or doping. Specifically, in TMDs, the SC filaments has been directly observed via scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) measurements [2]; in cuprates, magnetoresistance experiments on LSCO thin films [3, 4], spin susceptibilities [5] and specific heat [6] in YBCO all evidence a fragile SC state surviving at low temperatures in the charge density wave (CDW) state of the phase diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this work [7, 8], we studied the CDW-SC competition by means of Monte Carlo simulations. We use an anisotropic Heisenberg model on a two-dimensional square lattice that captures the basic symmetries of the problem: the out-of-plane component of the pseudospin sz encodes two possible charge ordered variants (up/down) and the in-plane component stands for the SC order parameter. We construct a phase diagram where the anisotropy term α introduced plays the same role as the magnetic field in real experiments and it can tune the transition from the topological BKT to the CDW (see Fig. 1). Importantly, we find the presence of impurities is necessary in order to stabilize the clustering of polycrystalline charge ordered domains and the appearance of filamentary superconductivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/image_prova.png&quot; alt=&quot;My image Name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] G. Venditti et al. Superfluid rigidity in filamentary superconductors, In preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] M. Spera et al. Phys. Rev. B 99, 155133 (2019).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] B. Leridon et al. New J. Phys. 22 073025 (2020).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4] S. Caprara et al. SciPost Phys. 8, 003 (2020).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5] R. Zhou et al. PNAS 1711445114 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6] J. Kačmarčík et al. Phys. Rev. Lett. 121, 167002 (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7] G. Venditti et al. Competition between charge order and superconductivity in 2d systems, In preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[8] G. Venditti et al. Filamentary superconductivity arising from the CDW-SC competition, In preparation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 3rd, 2022: Giulia Venditti</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">September 26th, 2022: Albert Samoilenka</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/albert-samoilenka.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="September 26th, 2022: Albert Samoilenka" /><published>2022-07-30T09:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T09:30:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/albert-samoilenka</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/albert-samoilenka.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;september-26th-2022-albert-samoilenka&quot;&gt;September 26th, 2022: Albert Samoilenka&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, September 26th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Albert Samoilenka&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;KTH&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boundary States and Enhanced Superconductivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard textbook picture describes the onset of superconductivity in a BCS model as a single phase transition. The picture relies on the microscopic derivation of the boundary conditions between a BCS superconductor and vacuum by De Gennes and later by Abrikosov. They concluded that the normal derivative of the order parameter is zero. Hence the superconducting order parameter should vanish near the boundary at the same temperature as in the bulk. I will show that there are additional boundary states that were missed in previous works. They are characterized by an increased superconducting gap near boundaries, which asymptotically decays in the bulk. Moreover, the gap survives near the sample boundaries at higher temperatures than in the bulk. Therefore, BCS superconductors have multiple critical points associated with separate phase transitions at the boundary and in the bulk. We will revise the microscopic derivation of superconductor-insulator boundary conditions for the Ginzburg-Landau model. These are shown to follow from considering the order parameter reflected in the boundary. We will also study how boundary states behave in the presence of pair-density-wave states or magnetic fields.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">September 26th, 2022: Albert Samoilenka</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">September 19th, 2022: Chris Halcrow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/chistopher-halcrow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="September 19th, 2022: Chris Halcrow" /><published>2022-07-30T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/chistopher-halcrow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/chistopher-halcrow.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;september-19th-2022-chris-halcrow&quot;&gt;September 19th, 2022: Chris Halcrow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, September 19th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Chris Halcrow&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;KTH, Royal Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topological Solitons and Their Moduli Spaces&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topological solitons (kinks, lumps, skyrmions, vortices, monopoles, hopfions, instantons, … ) are localised, finite-energy solutions of nonlinear PDEs who owe their existence and stability to the topology of the system. They are studied by a wide variety of physicists. I’ll try to explain why high-energy and mathematical physicist study them, and what problems they are interested in. In particular, we’ll study the moduli space manifold (solution space) and use it to describe soliton dynamics. This example will motivate some further applications and problems. I’ll end by suggesting how these insights might shine a light on solitons in condensed matter. The talk is designed to be accessible, with no prerequisite knowledge required.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">September 19th, 2022: Chris Halcrow</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">September 5th, 2022: Sudhansu Sekhar Mandal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/sudhansu-sekhar-mandal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="September 5th, 2022: Sudhansu Sekhar Mandal" /><published>2022-07-30T08:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T08:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/sudhansu-sekhar-mandal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/07/30/sudhansu-sekhar-mandal.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;september-5th-2022-sudhansu-sekhar-mandal&quot;&gt;September 5th, 2022: Sudhansu Sekhar Mandal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, September 5th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Sudhansu Sekhar Mandal&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iitkgp.ac.in/department/PH/faculty/ph-sudhansu&quot;&gt;Personal webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anomalous Re-entrant Quantized 5/2 Fractional Quantum Hall State&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although most of the fractional quantum Hall effect (FQHE) states in the lowest Landau level are well understood in terms of the composite fermion theory, the FQHE states in the second Landau level remain enigmatic. Amongst these, 5/2 state is the most intriguing as it is the cooperative system where the existence of Majorana edge mode was first proposed. Thermal Hall conductance [1] and shot-noise [2] experiments are in favour of the existence of such modes. However, the experimentally found topological order (on which the above quantities depend) is reported to be different from the theoretically predicted topological order for small or no Landau-level-mixing (LLM) which induces three-body interaction. Our exact-diagonalization study [3] reveals a topological phase transition from conventional low LLM phase to an anomalous re-entrant phase at higher LLM strength. Our predicted wave function which is found to have very high overlap with the exact ground state in this phase is a simple representative wave function for understanding this topological order. This wave function may be interpreted as two repulsive Bose-Einstein condensates of the composite bosons. However, there is no physical segregation between these two condensates because a complete symmetrisation of the composite bosons is explicitly considered. We attribute this novel phase to the experimentally observed topological order. We argue that the thermal Hall conductivity predicted by the wave function as \(\kappa_H = 2.5 \bigl( \frac{\pi^2 k_B^2 T}{3h} \bigr)\), as reported in the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] Banerjee et al, Nature (London) 559, 205 (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] Dutta et al, Science 375, 193 (2022).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] S. Das, S. Das, and S. S. Mandal, arXiv:2206.04419.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">September 5th, 2022: Sudhansu Sekhar Mandal</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">May 30th, 2022: Ivan Khaymovich</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/05/30/ivan-khaymovich.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="May 30th, 2022: Ivan Khaymovich" /><published>2022-05-30T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/05/30/ivan-khaymovich</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/05/30/ivan-khaymovich.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;may-30th-2022-ivan-khaymovich&quot;&gt;May 30th, 2022: Ivan Khaymovich&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, May 30th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we hosted a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Ivan Khaymovich&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Nordita&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/ivan-khaymovich/&quot;&gt;Personal webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Localization Beyond Convergence of Localized Perturbation Theory in Correlated Long-Range Systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the standard picture of Anderson localization transition in long-range (e.g. dipolar) systems [1, 2] has been argued from the following perspective. There have been reported [3-6] several counterintuitive examples of single-particle systems with long-range hopping, where almost all states are (at least power-law) localized even in a nominally ergodic regime, where the standard locator expansion breaks down [1, 2]. Some of these “new” models demonstrate critical behavior [3, 4] for disorder strengths below the ones at the Anderson transition in [1, 2]. In the other ones [6, 7] wave-function spatial decay rates obey a “mysterious” duality [6] mapping different powers of power-law bending [2]. The seminal paper on second-type models [7] has been unnoticed until recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the striking difference between the standard long-range models [1-2] and the new ones [3-8]? The systems [3-8] belong to a new universality class where correlations of hopping terms play a significant role in the localization properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my talk I address this intriguing question. I present a general approach applicable to all such models and uncover the role of correlations and the origin of the duality [A]. This method is based on the localization-delocalization principles both in the coordinate and in the momentum space. I will show that the so-called Mott’s criterion (which is shown to be the sufficient criterion of ergodic delocalization) and the Anderson criterion (which is shown to be the sufficient criterion of localization) are not complimentary. There is a gap between their regions of validity where the non-ergodic extended phases and the novel correlation-induced localization may occur. To illustrate the above mentioned principles, I will consider the models with power-law decaying hopping [1-2, 6-8, A-F], where the well-known example is the power-law random banding matrices (PLRBM).
The phenomenon of the correlation-induced localization [A] is just the very peak of the iceberg in this field. Recent steps in this direction made by us include the development of renormalization group approach to tackle systems with Euclidean random hopping [C], the effects of anisotropy [D], partial correlations [B, E, F], time-reversal symmetry breaking [G] on the above phenomenon. The range of systems is also not limited by the dipolar systems, but includes also the Weyl semimetals, ultracold atoms, Rydberg excitations in the optical traps and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] L. S. Levitov, Europhy. Lett. 9, 83 (1989); Phys. Rev. Lett. 64, 547 (1990).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] A. D. Mirlin, Y. V. Fyodorov, F.-M. Dittes, J. Quezada, and T. H. Seligman, Phys. Rev. E 54, 3221 (1996).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] H. K. Owusu, K. Wagh, and E. A. Yuzbashyan, J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 42, 035206 (2009).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4] A. Ossipov, J. Phys. A 46, 105001 (2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5] G. L. Celardo, R. Kaiser, and F. Borgonovi, Phys. Rev. B 94, 144206 (2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6] X. Deng, V. E. Kravtsov, G. V. Shlyapnikov and L. Santos, Phys. Rev. Lett. 120, 110602 (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7] A. L. Burin and L. A. Maksimov, JETP Lett. 50, 338 (1989).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[8] J. T. Cantin, T. Xu, and R. V. Krems, Phys. Rev. B 98, 014204 (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[A] P. Nosov, I. M. K., V. E. Kravtsov, “Correlation-induced localization”, Phys. Rev. B 99, 104203 (2019) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.01492&quot;&gt;arXiv:1810.01492&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[B] P. A. Nosov, I. M. K., “Robustness of delocalization to the inclusion of soft constraints in long-range random models”, Phys. Rev. B 99, 224208 (2019) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.11509&quot;&gt;arXiv:1904.11509&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[C] A. Kutlin, I. M. K., “Renormalization to localization without a small parameter”, SciPost Phys. 8, 049 (2020) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2001.06493&quot;&gt;arXiv:2001.06493&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[D] X. Deng, A. L. Burin, I. M. K., “Anisotropy-driven localization transition in quantum dipoles” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.00013&quot;&gt;arXiv:2002.00013&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[E] A. G. Kutlin, I. M. K., “Multifractality emergence in energy stratified random models” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.03864&quot;&gt;arxiv:2106.03864&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[F] W. C. Tang, I. M. K., “Non-ergodic delocalized phase with Poisson level statistics”, (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09700&quot;&gt;arXiv:2112.09700&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[G] V. Motamarri, A. S. Gorsky, I. M. K. “Time-reversal symmetry breaking, localization, and emergent multifractality in a Bethe-ansatz integrable model”, (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2112.05066&quot;&gt;arXiv:2112.05066&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">May 30th, 2022: Ivan Khaymovich</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">May 16th, 2022: Maria Hermanns</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/05/16/maria-hermanns.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="May 16th, 2022: Maria Hermanns" /><published>2022-05-16T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-16T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/05/16/maria-hermanns</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/05/16/maria-hermanns.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;may-16th-2022-maria-hermanns&quot;&gt;May 16th, 2022: Maria Hermanns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, May 16th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we hosted a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Maria Hermanns&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Stockholm University&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fate of Boundary Modes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One general hallmark of topological phases of matter is the existence of robust zero-energy boundary modes. The stability of the modes is ensured by so-called topological invariants, which in turn rely on the existence of an energy gap. In this talk, we discuss how much of this survives when the system becomes critical. In particular, we discuss how one may generalize topological invariants to systems without an energy gap, as well as the fate of boundary modes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">May 16th, 2022: Maria Hermanns</summary></entry></feed>