<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-05T11:30:04+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The JCMS series</title><subtitle>The Joint Condensed Matter Seminar (JCMS) series is organised by KTH Royal Insitute of Technology, Nordita, and Stockholm University.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">February 6th, 2022: Jonas Larson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/jonas-larson.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="February 6th, 2022: Jonas Larson" /><published>2022-10-12T17:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T17:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/jonas-larson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/jonas-larson.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;february-6th-2022-jonas-larson&quot;&gt;February 6th, 2022: Jonas Larson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, February 6th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Jonas Larson&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Stockholm University&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">February 6th, 2022: Jonas Larson</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">January 30th, 2022: Paolo Molignini</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/paolo-molignini.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January 30th, 2022: Paolo Molignini" /><published>2022-10-12T16:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T16:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/paolo-molignini</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/paolo-molignini.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;january-30th-2022-paolo-molignini&quot;&gt;January 30th, 2022: Paolo Molignini&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, January 30th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Paolo Molignini&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Stockholm University&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">January 30th, 2022: Paolo Molignini</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">January 23rd, 2022: Tim Wehling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/tim-wehling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January 23rd, 2022: Tim Wehling" /><published>2022-10-12T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T15:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/tim-wehling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/tim-wehling.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;january-23rd-2022-tim-wehling&quot;&gt;January 23rd, 2022: Tim Wehling&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, January 23rd, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Tim Wehling&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;University of Hamburg&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">January 23rd, 2022: Tim Wehling</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">January 12th, 2022: Felix von Oppen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/felix-von-oppen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January 12th, 2022: Felix von Oppen" /><published>2022-10-12T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/felix-von-oppen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/felix-von-oppen.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;january-12th-2022-felix-von-oppen&quot;&gt;January 12th, 2022: Felix von Oppen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, January 12th, 2022 from 13 to 14 we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Felix von Oppen&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Freie Universität Berlin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diode effects in current-biased Josephson junctions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current flow in electronic devices can be asymmetric with bias direction, a phenomenon underlying the utility of diodes and known as non-reciprocal charge transport. The promise of dissipationless electronics has recently stimulated the quest for superconducting diodes. Non-reciprocal Josephson junctions are particularly promising for device applications, for instance in the context of superconducting qubits. In this talk, I will discuss a recent experiment, in which non-reciprocity is observed as the result of introducing a single magnetic atom into the Josephson junction and use this as a starting point for developing a general theory of non-reciprocal transport in current-biased Josephson junctions. This will include a discussion of the symmetry requirements underlying non-reciprocal transport. I will also briefly describe a generalized derivation of the Keldysh action of Josephson junctions, which incorporates non-reciprocity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">January 12th, 2022: Felix von Oppen</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">December 12th, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/apoorv-tiwari.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December 12th, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari" /><published>2022-10-12T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/apoorv-tiwari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/apoorv-tiwari.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;december-12th-2022-apoorv-tiwari&quot;&gt;December 12th, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, December 12th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Apoorv Tiwari&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;KTH, Royal Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unifying Constructions of Non-Invertible Symmetries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization that global symmetry can be understood as the topological subsector of the spectrum of operators of a given QFT/ quantum system has led to new global symmetries that vastly generalize conventional group-like symmetries. In particular, various constructions of non-invertible (not group-like) symmetries have appeared in the literature in the last couple of years. All of these non-invertible symmetries are built from invertible symmetries and dualities (suitably interpreted). This makes one wonder whether all these constructions are actually different manifestations of an underlying uniform construction of non-invertible symmetries starting from invertible objects.  In this talk, I will present such a unified construction. The construction is based on new insights related to gauging global symmetries in quantum systems. Along the way, I will provide some examples based on Ising-type lattice models as well as pure gauge theories.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">December 12th, 2022: Apoorv Tiwari</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">December 5th, 2022: Alexander Buzdin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/alexander-buzdin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December 5th, 2022: Alexander Buzdin" /><published>2022-10-12T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/alexander-buzdin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/alexander-buzdin.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;december-5th-2022-alexander-buzdin&quot;&gt;December 5th, 2022: Alexander Buzdin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, December 5th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Alexander Buzdin&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;University of Bordeaux&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optical methods of flux manipulation in superconductors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the average properties of the vortex matter in superconductors can be tuned with magnetic fields, temperature or electric currents, handling of individual Abrikosov vortices remains challenging and has been demonstrated only with sophisticated scanning local probe microscopies. Recently we have proposed a far-field optical method based on local heating of the superconductor with a focused laser beam to realize a fast and precise manipulation of individual vortices, in the same way as with optical tweezers [1]. This open a way to create laser-driven Josephson junctions controlled by the optically driven Abrikosov vortex [2].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important challenge is on-demand optical generation of single flux quanta. We discuss a far-field optical method to generate permanent single vortices at any desired position in a superconductor. It is based on the fast quench following the absorption of a tightly focused laser pulse (so called Kibble-Zurek effect) that locally heats the superconductor above its critical temperature. We achieve ex-nihilo creation of a single vortex pinned at the center of the hotspot, while its counterpart opposite flux is trapped tens of micrometers away at its boundaries [3].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another method for the single flux quanta manipulation may be related with the so-called inverse Faraday effect - a circularly polarized radiation interacting with a superconducting condensate acts as an efffective magnetic field that can generate supercurrents and DC magnetic moments [4]. Using the time-dependent Ginzburg–Landau equation formalism, the current-carrying states of a small superconducting ring illuminated by such radiation are analysed [5]. Numerical simulations demonstrate the possibility to on-demand switch between current-carrying states in the superconductor by controlling the helicity of the electromagnetic field polarization [6]. This result opens the way to all-optical operation of superconducting devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/jcms.github.io/assets/images/fig-buzdin.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] I. S. Veshchunov, W. Magrini, S.V. Mironov, A.G. Godin, et al, Nature communications 7, 1-7 (2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] S. Mironov, E. Goldobin, D. Koelle, R., Kleiner, et al, Physical Review B 96, 214515 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] A. Rochet, V. Vadimov, W. Magrini, S. Thakur, et al, Nano Letters 20, 6488-6493 (2020).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4] S.V. Mironov, A.S. Mel’nikov, I.D. Tokman, V. Vadimov, et al. Physical Review Letters 126, 137002 (2021).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5] M.D. Croitoru, B. Lounis, A.I. Buzdin, Physical Review B 105, L020504 (2022).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6] M.D. Croitoru, S.V. Mironov, B. Lounis, A.I. Buzdin, Advanced Quantum Technologies, 2200054 (2022).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">December 5th, 2022: Alexander Buzdin</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/marin-bukov.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov" /><published>2022-10-12T11:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T11:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/marin-bukov</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/marin-bukov.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;november-28th-2022-marin-bukov&quot;&gt;November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, November 28th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Marin Bukov&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Max Planck Institute for the Physics of Complex Systems, Dresden&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-Correcting Quantum Many-Body Control using Reinforcement Learning with Tensor Networks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantum many-body control is a central milestone en route to harnessing quantum technologies. However, the exponential growth of the Hilbert space dimension with the number of qubits makes it challenging to classically simulate quantum many-body systems and consequently, to devise reliable and robust optimal control protocols. Here, we present a novel framework for efficiently controlling quantum many-body systems based on reinforcement learning (RL). We tackle the quantum control problem by leveraging matrix product states (i) for representing the many-body state and, (ii) as part of the trainable machine learning architecture for our RL agent. The framework is applied to prepare ground states of the quantum Ising chain, including critical states. It allows us to control systems far larger than neural-network-only architectures permit, while retaining the advantages of deep learning algorithms, such as generalizability and trainable robustness to noise. In particular, we demonstrate that RL agents are capable of finding universal controls, of learning how to optimally steer previously unseen many-body states, and of adapting control protocols on-the-fly when the quantum dynamics is subject to stochastic perturbations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">November 28th, 2022: Marin Bukov</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">November 18th, 2022: Patrick Lenggenhager</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/patrick-lenggenhager.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November 18th, 2022: Patrick Lenggenhager" /><published>2022-10-12T10:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T10:30:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/patrick-lenggenhager</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/patrick-lenggenhager.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;november-18th-2022-patrick-lenggenhager&quot;&gt;November 18th, 2022: Patrick Lenggenhager&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, November 18th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Lenggenhager&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;ETH, Zurich&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a hyperbolic drum towards hyperbolic topological insulators&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent development of hyperbolic band theory, which describes energy spectra of particles on hyperbolic lattices, revived interest in crystalline models embedded in negatively curved spaces and led to the emergence of hyperbolic lattices as a new paradigm of synthetic matter. A salient feature of hyperbolic band theory is the unusually large dimension of the momentum space: a two-dimensional hyperbolic lattice leads to an at least four-dimensional Brillouin zone. This potentially leads to novel types of topological matter. The theoretical interest has also sparked the search for suitable experimental realizations in different metamaterial platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this seminar, I will first give an introduction to the basic ideas of hyperbolic lattices and some of the subtleties arising before discussing two of our recent works. In the first, we experimentally realize an artificial hyperbolic space with constant negative curvature in an electric-circuit network and develop a set of methods to verify the effective hyperbolic metric [1]. More specifically, we consider the low-energy modes of a disk-shaped sample of a hyperbolic lattice, which we call “hyperbolic drum”, and reveal evidence of the negative curvature in both static and dynamical experiments. In the second, purely theoretical work, we take a first step towards analyzing topology in hyperbolic synthetic matter [2]. We formulate hyperbolic versions of two paradigmatic models of topological insulators, namely of (1) the Haldane model of a Chern insulator, and of (2) the Kane-Mele model of a time-reversal-symmetric topological insulator. Their non-trivial topology is revealed both in momentum space and real space invariants and we observe robust propagating metallic in-gap states at the boundary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] P. M. Lenggenhager, A. Stegmaier, L. K. Upreti, T. Hofmann, T. Helbig, A. Vollhardt, M. Greiter, C. H. Lee, S. Imhof, H. Brand, T. Kießling, I. Boettcher, T. Neupert, R. Thomale, and T. Bzdušek, Nat. Commun. 13, 4373 (2022).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] D. M. Urwyler, P. M. Lenggenhager, I. Boettcher, R. Thomale, T. Neupert, and T. Bzdušek, arXiv:2203.07292 (2022).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">November 18th, 2022: Patrick Lenggenhager</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">November 7th, 2022: Thomas Kvorning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/thomas-kvorning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November 7th, 2022: Thomas Kvorning" /><published>2022-10-12T10:10:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T10:10:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/thomas-kvorning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/thomas-kvorning.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;november-7th-2022-thomas-kvorning&quot;&gt;November 7th, 2022: Thomas Kvorning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, November 7th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Thomas Kvorning&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;KTH&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What question does Bell’s theorem address?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bell’s theorem is often cited as one of the most important results in quantum foundations. Still, there is a disagreement about what the theorem addresses. John Bell argued that the theorem concerns causality, while hidden variables are a tool in the derivation. Nevertheless, the first sentence of John Bell’s Wikipedia page states that Bell’s theorem concerns hidden variable theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will dedicate my presentation to the notion of local causality. Even though this seemingly is a familiar concept, failure to understand it is widespread and at the root of the mentioned disagreement.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">November 7th, 2022: Thomas Kvorning</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 24th, 2022: Loïc Herviou</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/loic-herviou.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 24th, 2022: Loïc Herviou" /><published>2022-10-12T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/loic-herviou</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jcms.github.io/2022/10/12/loic-herviou.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;october-24th-2022-loïc-herviou&quot;&gt;October 24th, 2022: Loïc Herviou&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, October 24th, 2022 from 11 am to 12 am we will host a seminar by &lt;strong&gt;Loïc Herviou&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;EPFL, Lausanne&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible restoration of particle-hole symmetry in the 5/2 Quantized Hall State at small magnetic field&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivated by the experimental observation of a quantized 5/2 thermal conductance at filling 5/2, a result incompatible with the theoretical predictions, we have pushed the expansion of the effective Hamiltonian of the 5/2 quantized Hall state to third-order in the Landau level mixing parameter.
&lt;br /&gt;
After a brief introduction on the FQHE and the physics of the 5/2 state, I will show that our exact diagonalization computations suggest that the energy differences between Pfaffian and AntiPfaffian states are significantly smaller than expected, and that the particle-hole symmetry might be restored in the experimental regime.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 24th, 2022: Loïc Herviou</summary></entry></feed>